# **Andrew Neudegg**

#### **Profile**

I am a creative and precise software engineer that enjoys tackling difficult problems and the satisfaction of a successful build. I have experience with distributed and blockchain based applications, management, software engineering, and I am driven to further discover the benefits and limitations of new or different technologies. I relish the opportunity for team work, discussions about data, and I am also partial to esports and great music. I enjoy scientific exploration and in particular, have an interest in using technology to refine our interactions with everyday life.

## What I am looking for

A role that will enable me to upgrade my existing leadership skills and help me take the next step in my career. My long-term goal is to hold the role of technical lead within a vibrant, ethical, and cohesive team; delivering meaningful software experiences to stakeholders. Working for a Post-trade Fintech startup has given me the opportunity to gain firsthand experience of some of the many roles that I would like to oversee and contribute to.

## **Work Experience**

February 2018-present: *RISE Financial Technologies (startup)*; Software Engineer.

- Produced functional analysis and design documentation for myself and others on the basis of business and client requirements.
- Reported to the CEO, CTO, Senior Developers and Team Leader for various projects, working closely with them to set out expectations.
- Proposed, delivered, and tested multiple projects for internal team use.
- Worked on deliverables with third party and inhouse blockchain solutions.
- Designed and delivered performance gains, bringing tooling and training back to the team.
- Encouraged cultural change within the team to consider performance and scalability as key aspects of a distributed systems behavior.
- Experience with effective pair programming.

2016-2017: Papa Johns; Lincoln, Supervisor.

- Trained new staff members in best practice.
- Successfully lead individuals from mixed backgrounds in periods of high volume, high pressure situations.

2011-2016: *WHSmith*; Sales Assistant, Supervisor.

- Earned company wide recognition for improving an 'at-risk' store.
- Assisted in training would-be supervisors in the skills required to lead.
- Trained new and existing staff members in the best practice and procedures for them and their team to enable them to support their store.
- Reported to senior and area managers directly to inform of progress and reasonable expectations.
- Interpreted and distilled company briefings to plan work for individual team members around their working hours and the store's footfall.

#### **Education**

- MSc Computer Science; Distinction, University of Lincoln 2016-2017. Dissertation on behavioural analysis of Moroccan Barbary Macaques using novel data science techniques; Distinction.
- BSc Psychology; Upper Second, University of Lincoln 2013-2016. Dissertation on global P2P digital piracy as a meter for human behaviour; Distinction.

### **Software Engineer Experience**

- Experience using Windows and Ubuntu development environments, including managing Ubuntu servers.
- Implemented a Gitlab CI environment for Python, Go and Java applications that made up the Business-critical application suite. Providing training to team members on maintaining and using the CI environment.
- Constructed and maintained RESTful API's for internal and external use.
- Lead investigations into migrating open source libraries to more recent versions, researched vulnerabilities, and ensured license compatibility with the firms release policy.
- Responsible for sourcing of open source components, performing risk assessments where required.
- IBM's Hyperledger Fabric Blockchain, using Chaincode (Fabric's smart contract equivalent) and SDKs.
- Worked on two products that focussed on using Blockchains for Post-trade settlement.
- Robust language knowledge of Python, Go, Java and C#, with an understanding of C++, Cython, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and MATLAB. Additional knowledge with the scripting language Bash.
- Experience with statistical software such as WEKA, SPSS, SciPy; including structuring large datasets using Relational, NoSQL, and flat file databases. Practical experience with Clustering, Regression and data modelling.
- Experience using source control tools such as git, SVN and virtualisation tools like docker and VMware.